JOE BELMONTE

- **☑** joseph.belmonte@gmail.com
- www.josephbelmonte.com
- **** 781-858-3236
- **♥** 35 School Street Milton, MA 02186
- in joe-belmonte
- (?) joebelmonte

Skills

JavaScript

HTML

CSS

React

Bootstrap

Node

Ruby

Rails

Ember

Git / GitHub

Handlebars

Heroku

jQuery

Projects

Geography Bee Map-Based Quiz Game

State Trotter
Bucket List by US
State

Movie Night Personal Movie Database

Tic Tac Toe Simple Tic Tac Toe Game

For details and links to all projects, visit josephbelmonte.com

Summary

I want to pursue my love of technology and great software by combining the skills I developed over 15 years in market research for the financial services sector - including a high level of attention to detail, and the ability to excel in a fast-paced, deadline-driven environment - with the coding skills I've learned at General Assembly.

Experience

General Assembly

Boston

Web Development Immersive

Mar 2017 to Jun 2017

- Completed a rigorous 3 month coding boot camp focused on full-stack web development.
- Designed and built several full-stack single-page web applications using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript for front end and Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, and MongoDB for back end.
- Worked in teams and individually using Agile methodology and Git/GitHub for version control.

Market Metrics

Boston, MA

Director of Global Research

May 2015 to Mar 2017

Responsible for all survey-based research conducted in the U.S. and Europe, including:

- Ensuring timely and accurate completion and delivery of survey results for over 20 yearly studies requiring roughly 30,000 interviews per year
- Managing a team of roughly 25 Analysts, Associates, and Associate Directors working within the group

Director of Operations

Sep 2011 to May 2015

Responsible for the internal operations for all of Market Metrics via direct or indirect management of a team of roughly 35 employees, including:

- Internal Management, Resource Allocations
- Professional Development, Promotions, and Compensation
- Recruiting and New Hire Training

Associate

Jan 2007 to Sep 2011

- Led development of a completely new syndicated research study that examined satisfaction and productivity of field and internal wholesalers for Asset Management and Insurance Companies.
- Led the launch of Market Metrics' first research outside of the U.S.
- Managed all phases of the Life Insurance syndicated research cycle, from survey design to analysis of results.

Education

Dartmouth College

BA Economics and History 2002

GPA: 3.6. Coursework included Microeconomics, Macroeconomics, Statistics, Econometrics, Financial Markets and Institutions, International Trade; US History and foreign relations.